spiritualsingles.com 2018-08-12

# Privay Terms and Conditions

## OUR COMMITMENT TO YOU

At Conscious Dating Network, which owns and operates Spiritual Singles, we highly value your privacy and it is and has always been a top priority for us. We have designed and built our websites with a focus on your privacy so that you can focus on building conscious connections and meaningful relationships.

We appreciate that you put your trust in us when you provide us with your information and we do not take this lightly.

**We strive to be transparent in the way we process your data.** Because we use many of the same online services you do, we know that insufficient information and overly complicated language are common issues in privacy policies. We take the exact opposite approach: we have written our Privacy Policy and related documents in plain language. We actually want you to read our policies and understand our privacy practices!

**We work hard to keep your information secure.** We have teams dedicated to keeping your data safe and secure. We constantly update our security practices and invest in our security efforts to enhance the safety of your information.

Conscious Dating Network consists of several spiritual and green online dating sites all sharing one database of members, like different doorways into the same house. In other words, we have different domains (doorways), some of which are marketed directly by us and others that are marketed by third parties. All members are saved in one database and all members have access to all members from all domains automatically. Members only need to join one site to have access to all. We do this for marketing purposes so as to provide our members with more possibilities to meet and ultimately create conscious connections and relationships.

## PRIVACY POLICY

Welcome to Conscious Dating Network's Privacy Policy. Thank you for taking the time to read it.

We appreciate that you trust us with your information and we intend to always keep that trust. This starts with making sure you understand the information we collect, why we collect it, how it is used and your choices regarding your information. This Policy describes our privacy practices in plain language, keeping legal and technical jargon to a minimum.

This Privacy Policy applies beginning May 25, 2018.   
EFFECTIVE DATE: May 25, 2018 

The company that is responsible for your information under this Privacy Policy (the "data controller") is:  
Conscious Dating Network, LLC  
404 North Mount Shasta Blvd #318  
Mount Shasta, CA 96067  

This Privacy Policy applies to the dating websites and other services operated by Conscious Dating Network. For simplicity, we refer to all of these as our "services" in this Privacy Policy. To make it extra clear, we've added links to this Privacy Policy on all applicable services.

It goes without saying, we can't help you develop meaningful connections without some information about you, such as basic profile details and the types of people you'd like to meet. If you'd like additional info, we go into more detail below.

**_Information you give us_**

You choose to give us certain information when using our services. This includes: 

  * When you create an account (profile), you provide us with at least your email address, login credentials, as well as some basic details necessary for the service to work, such as your gender, date of birth, type of relationship you are seeking, marital status...,etc.
  * When you complete your profile, you can share with us additional information, such as details on your personality, lifestyle, interests and other details about you, as well as content such as photos and videos. To add certain content, like pictures or videos, you may allow us to access your camera or photo album. Some of the information you choose to provide us may be considered "special" or "sensitive" in certain jurisdictions, for example your racial or ethnic origins, sexual orientation and religious beliefs. By choosing to provide this information, you consent to our processing of that information.
  * When you subscribe to a paid service you provide us or our payment service provider with information, such as your debit or credit card number or other financial information.
  * When you participate in surveys or focus groups, you give us your insights into our products and services, responses to our questions and testimonials.
  * When you choose to participate in our promotions, events or contests, we collect the information that you use to register or enter.
  * If you contact our customer support, membercare and/or webmaster team, we save your email and our response in case we need to refer back to it for additional support, guidance or clarification for either you or us.
  * Of course, we also store your messages, hellos and live chats with other members as well as the content you publish in your essay answers, as part of the operation of the services.

**In addition to the information you provide us directly, we receive information about you from others, including:**

  * **Other Members**  
Other Conscious Dating Network members may provide information about you as they use our services. For instance, we may collect information about you from other members if they contact us about you. 

**Information collected when you use our services**

When you use our services, we collect information about which features you've used, how you've used them and the devices you use to access our services. See below for more details: 

  * **Usage Information**   
We collect information about your activity on our services, for instance how you use them (e.g., date and time you logged in, features you've been using, searches, clicks and pages which have been shown to you, referring webpage address, advertising that you click on) and how you interact with other members (e.g., members you connect and interact with, time and date of your exchanges, number of messages you send and receive). 
  * **Device information**   
We collect information from and about the device(s) you use to access our services, including: 
    * hardware and software information such as IP address, device ID and type, device-specific and apps settings and characteristics, app crashes, advertising IDs (such as Google's AAID and Apple's IDFA, both of which are randomly generated numbers that you can reset by going into your device' settings), browser type, version and language, operating system, time zones, identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser (e.g., IMEI/UDID and MAC address);
    * information on your wireless and mobile network connection, like your service provider and signal strength;
    * information on device sensors such as accelerometers, gyroscopes and compasses.

We use and may allow others to use cookies and similar technologies (e.g., web beacons, pixels) to recognize you and/or your device(s). You may read our Cookie Policy for more information on why we use them (such as authenticating you, remembering your preferences and settings, analyzing site traffic and trends, delivering and measuring the effectiveness of advertising campaigns, allowing you to use social features) and how you can better control their use, through your browser settings and other tools. 

The main reason we use your information is to deliver and improve our services. Additionally, we use your info to help keep you safe and to provide you with advertising that may be of interest to you. Read on for a more detailed explanation of the various reasons we use your information, together with practical examples. 

**To administer your account and provide our services to you**

  * Create and manage your account
  * Provide you with customer support and respond to your requests
  * Complete your transactions
  * Communicate with you about our services, including order management and billing

**To help you connect better with other members**

  * Analyze your profile and that of other members to recommend member Matches whom meet your criteria
  * Show members' profiles to one another

**To serve you relevant offers and ads**

  * Administer contests, discounts or other offers
  * Develop, display and track content and advertising tailored to your interests on our services and on other sites
  * Communicate with you by email, phone or mobile device about products or services that we think may interest you

**To improve our services and develop new ones**

  * Administer focus groups and surveys
  * Conduct research and analysis of members' behavior to improve our services and content (for instance, we may decide to change the look and feel or even substantially modify a given feature based on members' behavior)
  * Develop new features and services (for example, we may decide to build a new interests-based feature further to requests received from members).

**To prevent, detect and fight fraud or other illegal or unauthorized activities**

  * Address ongoing or alleged misbehavior on and off-platform
  * Perform data analysis to better understand and design countermeasures against these activities
  * Retain data related to fraudulent activities to prevent against recurrences

**To ensure legal compliance**

  * Comply with legal requirements
  * Assist law enforcement
  * Enforce or exercise our rights, for example our Terms

To process your information as described above, we rely on the following legal bases:

  * Provide our service to you: Most of the time, the reason we process your information is to perform the contract that you have with us. For instance, as you go about using our service to build conscious connections, and relationships we use your information to maintain your account and your profile, to make it viewable to other members and recommend other members to you. 
  * Legitimate interests: We may use your information where we have legitimate interests to do so. For instance, we analyze members' behavior on our services to continuously improve our offerings, we suggest offers we think might interest you, and we process information for administrative, fraud detection and other legal purposes. 

Since our goal is to help you make conscious connections, and relationships, the main sharing of members' information is, of course, with other members. We also share some members' information with service providers and partners who assist us in operating the services and, in some cases, legal authorities. Read on for more details about how your information is shared with others. 

  * **With other members**

You share information with other members when you voluntarily disclose information on the service (including your public profile). Please be careful with your information and make sure that the content you share is stuff that you're comfortable being publically viewable since neither you nor we can control what others do with your information once you share it. We ask that you do not post any contact info (on your profile) that could allow others to contact you directly (such as email address, phone number, social media info, business name, your real name...etc..) 

If you choose to hide your profile, then it will be hidden from view of all members. Your member "card" with your basic info (not your full profile) may be visible to some members, for example, if another member searches for you by username, or if you have email messages with members and one of these members clicks on your profile link from their Inbox. In these instances, the member will see your member card with a note that you have hidden your profile. 

  * **With our service providers and partners**

We use third parties to help us operate and improve our services. These third parties assist us with various tasks, including data hosting and maintenance, analytics, marketing, advertising and payment processing. 

We follow a strict vetting process prior to engaging any service provider or working with any partner. All of our service providers and partners must agree to strict confidentiality obligations. 

  * **With other Conscious Dating Network dating sites**

Spiritual Singles is part of the Conscious Dating Network of sister sites which, as of the date of this Privacy Policy, includes the following websites: 

**Sites marketed by Conscious Dating Network:**

SpiritualSingles.com  
SpiritualSingles.co.uk  
SpiritualSingles.com.au  
SpiritualSingles.ca  
GreenSingles.com  
PlanetEarthSingles.com  
ConsciousSingles.com   

**Privately Labeled Sites marketed by third parties (all sites are owned by Conscious Dating Network):**  
PlanetEarthSingles.com.au  
NaturalAwakeningsSingles.com  
ConsciousMatch.com  
SpiritualMatchmaking.com  
SoulfulMatch.com  
NewAgeConnections.com  
OmDating.com  
AscendingHearts.com  

**Members of a Privately Labeled site within Conscious Dating Network**

Each Privately Labeled Site marketer (person or company responsible for marketing any given Privately Labeled Site in the Conscious Dating Network --see list above) has access to a limited amount of information associated with those members who joined any given Privately Labeled Site. The Privately Labeled Site marketer has access to the following information for only the members associated with the site they market/promote: marketing source, name, username, location, gender, age, join date, last login date, subscription date (when applicable), subscription term (when applicable), and email address (only for AscendingHearts.com). 

  * **For corporate transactions**

We may transfer your information if we are involved, whether in whole or in part, in a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control.

  * **When required by law**

We may disclose your information if reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with a legal process, such as a court order, subpoena or search warrant, government / law enforcement investigation or other legal requirements; (ii) to assist in the prevention or detection of crime (subject in each case to applicable law); or (iii) to protect the safety of any person. 

  * **To enforce legal rights**

We may also share information: (i) if disclosure would mitigate our liability in an actual or threatened lawsuit; (ii) as necessary to protect our legal rights and legal rights of our members, business partners or other interested parties; (iii) to enforce our agreements with you; and (iv) to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing. 

We want you to be in control of your information, so we have provided you with the following tools:

  * Access / Update tools in the service. Tools and account settings that help you to access, rectify or delete information that you provided to us and that's associated with your account directly within the service. Most everything, including mail notification settings, hiding your profile, subscription info, personal info, deleting your profile...etc. can be accessed, edited or deleted on the ACCOUNT page after logging in (under the MORE menu bar drop down). Any profile information including your answers to multiple-choice questions and your essay answers can be edited or deleted on the "My Profile" page (under the MORE menu bar drop down).If you have any question in regard to those tools and/or options or settings, please contact our customer care team for help here.
  * Deletion. You can delete your account by using the corresponding functionality directly on the service (on the ACCOUNT page).

We want you to be aware of your privacy rights. Here are a few key points to remember:

  * Reviewing your information. Applicable privacy laws may give you the right to review the personal information we keep about you (depending on the jurisdiction, this may be called right of access, right of portability or variations of those terms). You can request a copy of your personal information by putting in such a request [here](mailto:Support@ConsciousDatingNetwork.com)
  * Updating your information. If you believe that the information we hold about you is inaccurate or that we are no longer entitled to use it and want to request its rectification, deletion or object to its processing, please contact us here.

Keep in mind, we may reject requests for certain reasons, including if the request is unlawful or if it may infringe on trade secrets or intellectual property or the privacy of another user. 

Also, we may not be able to accommodate certain requests to object to the processing of personal information, notably where such requests would not allow us to provide our service to you anymore. For instance, we cannot provide our service if we do not have your date of birth, gender and sexual orientation.

  * Accountability. In certain countries, including in the European Union, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how we process your personal information. The data protection authority you can lodge a complaint with notably may be that of your habitual residence, where you work or where we are established.

If you are a California resident, you can request a notice disclosing the categories of personal information about you that we have shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. To request this notice, please submit your request [here](mailto:Support@ConsciousDatingNetwork.com).Please allow 30 days for a response. For your protection and the protection of all of our members, we may ask you to provide proof of identity before we can answer such a request.

We work hard to protect you from unauthorized access to or alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information. As with all technology companies, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will always remain secure. We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and regularly review our information collection, storage and processing practices to update our physical, technical and organizational security measures.

  * We may suspend your use of all or part of the services without notice if we suspect or detect any breach of security. If you believe that your account or information is no longer secure, please notify us immediately [here](mailto:Support@ConsciousDatingNetwork.com)

We keep your personal information only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes (as laid out in Section 5 and as permitted by applicable law). In practice, we delete or anonymize your information 2 years after your profile has been deleted (either by us or you), unless: 

  1. We must keep it to comply with applicable law;
  2. We must keep it to evidence our compliance with applicable law;
  3. There is an outstanding issue, claim or dispute requiring us to keep the relevant information until it is resolved;  
or
  4. The information must be kept for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud prevention and enhancing members' safety and security. For example, information may need to be kept to prevent a user who was banned for unsafe behavior or security incidents from opening a new account.

Keep in mind that even though our systems are designed to carry out data deletion processes according to the above guidelines, we cannot promise that all data will be deleted within a specific timeframe due to technical constraints. 

Our services are restricted to members who are 18 years of age or older. We do not permit members under the age of 18 on our platform and we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18. If you suspect that a user is under the age of 18, please use the reporting mechanism available through the service.

Because we're always looking for new and innovative ways to help you build meaningful connections, this policy may change over time. We will notify you before any material changes take effect so that you have time to review the changes. 

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, here's how you can reach us: Online: [here](mailto:marketing@ConsciousDatingNetwork.com)

By mail (post):   
Privacy Officer  
Conscious Dating Network  
404 N Mount Shasta Blvd #318  
Mount Shasta, CA 96067
